Guide to the Luis Leal Papers, 1946-1985
Department of Special Collections
Luis Leal Papers,
1946-1985
Special Collections M761
Leal, Luis, 1907-
67 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Gift of Luis Leal, 1989
BIOGRAPHY
Luis Leal was born in Linares, Nuevo León, México on 17 September 1907. At the time of the mexican revolution, he emigrated to the United States, and established his residence in Chicago, where he continued his education.
On september 1936 he married Gladys Clemens. From this marriage they had two sons, Antonio and Luis Alonso.
In 1943 LuisLeal joined the United States Army, and was sent to the Pacific for two years. After his service in the Philippines at war's end, he continued his doctoral work at the University of Chicago and won his degree in Philosophy and Belles Lettres in 1950.
In 1951, he served as President of the Chicago Chapter of the American Association of Teachers of Spanish and Portuguese (AATSP), in 1952 he served as President of the Chicago Society of Romance Language Teachers, and in 1953, as Chairman of a Spanish section for the South Central Modern Language Association (the SCMLA).
Luis Leal held a number of teaching positions. From Instructor, Assistant Professor and Associate Professor at the University of Chicago, University of Illinois, Visiting Professor at UCSB and UCLA, Visiting Professor/Lecturer at the University of Chicago, University of Arizona, University of Wisconsin, National University of Mexico, Middlebury College, University of Arizona NDEA Institute, Guadalajara, México, and Stanford Univeristy.
Surrounded by mexican ambience, Doctor Luis Leal lives in Santa Bárbara with his gentle wife. His house like his heart continues open to share with disciples and friends the literary topics, memories of classrooms and the destiny of man.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The Luis Leal papers document the personal and academic activities of a literary historiographer, mexican writer, and critic.
Director of the Research Center for Chicano Studies at U.C. Santa Barbara and Professor Emeritus at the University of Illinois, Urbana, Leal has achieved a record of distinction as Professor of Spanish-American literature and has authored numerous books and hundreds of journal articles dealing with Latin American and Chicano literature. Especially noteworthy articles on Chicano literature include "Mexican American literature: a historical perspective," and "The problem of identifying Chicano literature."
By the time that Professor Leal began to study Chicano literature, he was one of the most respected critics of Latin American literature, and in particular the Mexican short story. The prestigious--and unfortunately now defunct--Mexican publishing house of Andre had published five books of his: Breve historia del cuento mexicano (1956), Antología del cuento mexicano (1957), Bibliografía del cuento mexicano (1958), Mariano Azuela: vida y obra (1961), and Historia del cuento hispanoamericano (1966). With these books, and many others published in the United States and Latin America, together with the innumerable articles and monographs which appeared in all the best academic periodicals, Leal built an admirable body of work, solid and systematic.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - Subseries A: General correspondence -1946-1988
    - April 1946 - Dec. 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Jan. 1954 - Jun. 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 1957-Dec. 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Jan. 1959-Dec.1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Jan. 1961-Dec. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Jan. 1963-Dec. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jan. 1964-Dec.1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jan. 1965-Dec. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Jan. 1966-Feb. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Mar. 1967-Dec. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 1968-Dec. 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Jan. 1969-Dec. 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Jan. 1970-Dec. 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Jan. 1971-Dec. 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Jan. 1972-Dec. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Jan. 1973-Dec. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Jan. 1974-Dec. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Jan. 1975-Dec. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Jan. 1976-May 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Jun. 1976-Dec.1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 1977-Apri. 1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - May 1977-Dec. 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Jan. 1978-Jun. 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Jul. 1978-Dec. 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Jan. 1979-Dec. 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Jan. 1980-Dec. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Jan. 1981-Dec. 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Jan. 1982-Dec. 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Jan. 1983-Dec. 1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 1984-Feb.1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Mar. 1984-Dec. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Jan. 1985-Dec. 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Jan. 1986-Apr. 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - May 1986-Dec. 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Jan. 1987-Dec. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Jan. 1988-Dec. 1988 Box (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B: EL NACIONAL correspondence - 1963-1967
    - Feb. 1963-Sept. 1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Series 2: Manuscripts of major works
  - Subseries A: Luis Leal unpublished book manuscripts
    - Incomplete transcription of 1620 edition of Francisco Bramón: Los Sirgueros de la Virgen sin original pecado. (see complete text on microfilm.) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Breve historia de la cultura en hispanoamérica (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cuentos de hispanoamérica (15). Realidad y fantasía (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Research notes for book on Juan Huarte y Navarro (Huarte de San Juan) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished Ph.D. thesis, University of Chicago, 1950. "El cuento y la leyenda en las crónicas de la Nueva España." (not for publication) pp. 1-185 (cont...) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Unpublished Ph.D. thesis, University of Chicago, 1950. "El cuento y la leyenda en las crónicas de la Nueva Espa~na." (not for publication) pp. 186-403 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Copy of above. (not for publication) pp. 1-309 (cont...) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Copy of above. (not for publication) pp. 310-402 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Materials for "Pequeña antología de sonetos mexicanos" with selection and introduction by Luis Leal. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Materials from Latin American authors for book on "Teoría y crítica del cuento." Introduction and selection by Luis Leal. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Master's Degree Dissertation on Amado Nervo, University of Chicago, June 1941. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Text and materials for book on "The History of the mexican short story." "Cuento-prehispánico" (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Materials and manuscripts for textbook on "Cuentos y leyendas" (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Incomplete manuscript for an analysis of Mariano Azuela: Los de abajo (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Materials for a textbook entitled "Cuentos y diálogos" (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Original manuscript and page proofs of the anthology "Cuentos mexicanos de hoy". Unpublished by Monticello Press. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished materials for Bibliography of Mexican Literature. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished and incomplete manuscript for book "La novela mexicana" (in spanish) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Short stories by mexican authors for anthology (in spanish) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Materials for anthology "Cuentistas de Jalisco" (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Ruiz de Alarcón (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Work in progress on book on José Rubén Romero (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Anthology of mexican literature." To have been published in collaboration with Professor John S. Brushwood by Pan American Union. (pp. 1-189) (cont...) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Anthology of mexican literature." To have been published in collaboration with Professor John S. Brushwood by Pan American Union. (pp. 190-379) (cont...) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Anthology of mexican literature." To have been published in collaboration with Professor John S. Brushwood by Pan American Union. (pp. 380-577) (cont...) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Anthology of mexican literature." To have been published in collaboration with Professor John S. Brushwood by Pan American Union. (also, folder of additional manuscripts materials for above) (cont...) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "Anthology of mexican literature." To have been published in collaboration with Professor John S. Brushwood by Pan American Union. (also, folder of additional manuscript materials for above) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Unpublished manuscript for book "Francisco Rojas González, sus mejores cuentos" (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Incomplete manuscript and materials for book on Alfonso Reyes. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Materials for anthology on mexican culture. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished manuscript for "La leyenda literaria mexicana (estudio y bibliografía). (cont...) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished manuscript for. "La leyenda literaria mexicana (estudio y bibliografía). (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Materials for anthology on "Perfiles mexicanos). (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Unpublished manuscript for "Diccionario de autores mexicanos". (cont....) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Unpublished manuscript for "Diccionario de autores mexicanos". (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Incomplete manuscript and materials for book "El español en México". (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Xerox copy of Antología del cuento mexicano (revised and unpublished). (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Incomplete manuscript for antología de poesía hispanoamericana (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Lecturas recreativas (textbook). (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Historia de la literatura mexicana" - Unpublished manuscript and materials for History of mexican literatura, completed to and including period of independence. (see files for research notes on "Historia de la literatura mexicana" - I, II, III. (pp. 1-87) (cont....) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Historia de la literatura mexicana" - Unpublished manuscript and materials for a History of mexican literature, completed to and including period of independence. (see file for research notes on "Historia de la literatura mexicana" - I, II, III. (pp. 88-173). (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - HLM - I Literatura indígenas. (cont....) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - HLM - I Literatura indígenas. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - HLM - II (XVI) A. Cronistas. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - HLM - II (XVI) B. La poesía. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - HLM - III (Siglo XVIII). (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - HLM - IV (Siglo XVIII) Rococó, 1700-1750. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - HLM - V Neoclasicismo, 1759-1805. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - HLM - VI Epoca de la independencia, 1805-1835. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - HLM - VII De la independencia a la reforma, 1836-1867. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - HLM - VIII De la reforma a la dictadura, 1867-1877. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - HLM - IX La dictadura (Del romanticismo al realismo), 1877-1910 (A). (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - HLM - IX La dictadura (El modernismo), 1865-1895 (B). (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - HLM - X Epoca de la revolución, 1910-1940. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - HLM - XI Epoca contemporánea. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - HLM Notas y apuntes. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - HLM Manuscripts and notes. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - HLM Bibliography. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Anonymous, original, unpublished short story manuscripts. 12 authors designated by numbers or pseudonym.
    - "Don Segundo Sombra". (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "Mairena". (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - _ _ Algunos dizque cuentos "El cuento del Noyolo". (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "Ixtlamachilztli". (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "Huacho". (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - #343 "Cronicas de Mariel" p.1-105. (cont....) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - #343 "Cronicas de Mariel" p.106-210. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Juan Tovar" Los misterios del reino (cuentos) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Zipit" Cuentos de la vida y el insomnio. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - #331 Tiempos difíciles (11 pp.) El Sr. Jiménez (16 pp.) Tropología (10 pp.) Frente a la Bahía (14 pp.) Un sábado como otro cualquiera (9 pp.) Divertimento (9 pp.) Postville, Ill (13 pp.) El Cementerio de Colón (8 pp.) El poder de la autosugestión (5 pp.) cont.... (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - #331 Un encuentro casual (6 pp.) Viaje al interior de la Isla (19 pp.) Un cuento (8 pp.) La editorial (11 pp.) El escándolo de la TV (21 pp.) El juicio de Dallas (14 pp.) El extranjero (19 pp.) Lo inverosímil (9 pp.) Hotel Morocco (6 pp.) (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - #337 "8 relatos piadosos" pp. 1-151. (cont....) (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - #337 "8 relatos piadosos" pp. 152-303. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - #321 "Fragmentos de las memorias del hombre". (pp. 1-120). (cont....) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - #321 "Fragmentos de las memorias del hombre" (pp. 121-240). (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - #306 Concurso "Letras de Oro" Universidad de Miami. Categoría: Cuento. Titulo: "Información sobre la ruta 1". (pp. 1-120) (cont....) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - #306 Concurso "Letras de Oro" Universidad de Miami. Categoría: Cuento. Titulo: "Información sobre la ruta 1". (pp. 121-242). (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 19 Short stories by various authors: #36 - La Inmortalidad de Purificación Alvarado. #51 - La Muerte del viejo Oñate. #54 - La Segunda Independencia: cuento escrito por Crescencio Facundo (Seudónimo). #66 - La urna. #117 - Dibujando a Dios en el tiempo, (cuento) Seudónimo: Pigmalión. #144 - El Paseo. Seudónimo: Alcotan. #153 - Concurso del cuento Esperante. Titulo: "La animita". Seudónimo: Mar. #158 - Te quise desde que te desarrugaste. (Caro Chilensis). #233 - Redención. #316 - Dever antes que vida. cont.... (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 19 Short stories by various authors: #342 - El Canto de las sirenas, por Anticefálico, para Beatriz. #352 - Tres tiempos en la vida de Sergia, por Xenófilo. #360 - Penelope Criolla. #362 - El Velorio. #366 - "Erase una vez...." #321 - Sebastián Knight/ Off side. #338 - Concurso del cuento Esperante: "Un nuevo sol", Jesús de la Cruz. #403 - El Compañero de Santiago, por Charlie 50. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Subseries C: Unpublished (as far as we know) manuscripts by authors and researchers: (Not Luis Leal)
    - Paulo de Carvalho Neto. Suomi (book). (pp. 1-204). (cont....) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Paulo de Carvalho Neto. Suomi (book). (p.205-408). (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Jorge Pratt 19th Century mexican literature (see Box 19-Folder 1) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Guillermo Villarreal. Amor, poesía y revolución en la obra de Efraín Huerta (manuscript). (pp. 1-119) (cont....) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Guillermo Villarreal. Amor, poesía y revolución en la obra de Efraín Huerta (manuscript). (pp. 120-237) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Joan Rea Green. La estructura del narrador en la novela hispanoaméricana contemporánea (manuscript). (pp. 1-92) (cont....) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Joan Rea Green. La estructura del narrador en la novela hispanoaméricana contemporánea (manuscript). (pp. 93-185) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Andrés Valdespino. Los cuentos amargos de Julián del Casal. Reynaldo Jiménez. Realidad y mitificación: El narrador niño en Los ríos profundos. A. M. Vazquez Bigi. Los conflictos psíquicos y religiosos de El hermano Asno. (also notes for above). H. Castillo. Mercaderes en el templo, obra inédita de Eduardo Barrios. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - C. Michael Waag. The figure of the Shaman in the works of Demetrio Aguilera-Malta. Marvin D'Ludo. A propósito de la ciencia ficción rioplatense. Isaías Lerner. El Diccionario de don Antonio de Alcedo y la Ilustración. Gerard Behague. Afro-brazilian cult musics: Regional versus national trends. Janina Montero. Historia y novela en hispanoamérica: El lenguaje de la ironía. Janina Montero. Novela e historia: Augusto Roa Bastos, Alejo Carpentier y Gabriel García Márquez. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Rolando J. Romero. El incesto y la liberación del yo: a propósito de Cien Años de soledad y Sobre héroes y tumbas. Juan Cruz Mendizabal. The role of fantasy in the works of García Márquez and the new latin american novel. Michael Palencia-Roth. Tres metamorfosis míticas en El otoño del patriarca: intertextualidades. Michael Palencia-Roth. El círculo hermenéuitico en El otoño del patriarca. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Joaquín Roy. Hacia una poética del ensayo hispanoaméricano. Kirsten F. Nigro. The grotesque world of José Donoso. Thomas Franz: Unamuno and Díaz Rodríguez's Sangre patricia: The Case for Mutual Borrowing. Claude Owen. Darío and Heine. Publio González-Rodas. Presencia de Sarmiento en Rubén Darío. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - José M. Alonso. Rubén y ella. Sandra Messinger Cypess. Preface from Studies in Romance Languages and Literatures: Essays critical and Cotactual. (to be published by Coronado Press, Kansas) Ernesto Prado Velásquez. Acu~na, Manuel (1849-1873). Biografía. Neal A. Wiegman. Notes on the Gringo. Summary. Clemente Palma. Breves notas biográficas. Graciela Palau de Nemes. Los cuentos fantásticos "Las fuerzas extra~nas" de Lugones. Su modernismo. Alejandra De Grazia. William Henry Hudson, costumbrista. Andrés Avellaneda. El impacto del peronismo en la narrativa argentina contemporánea. Forma y literaria e ideología en Sobre héroes y tumbas de Ernesto Sábato y un Responso de Juan José Saer. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Raymond D. Sousa. José María Heredia: The Poet and the Ideal of Liberty. (2 copies) Roberto E. Wilson. Dial M for Mexico. Michael Palencia-Roth. Cannibalism and the New Man of Latin America in the 15th and 16th Century European Imagination. Roy L. Tanner. Las expresíones alternativas y perifrásticas en la prosa de Ricardo Palma: Una clave estilística. (2 copies) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Rima Vallbona. Bibliografía de Eunice Odio: Rescate de un poeta. George Small. Proposal. David Lagmanovich. Estructura e efecto en "La migala" de Juan José Arreola. (2 copies) Theda M. Herz. Las fuentes cultas de la sátira del Confabulario. (2 copies) Inés Arredondo. Alva Ixtlilxochitl, Fernando de. Raúl H. Padilla. Altamirano, Ignacio Manuel. Ma. del C.M. El doble. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Ignacio R. Galbis. Hugo Rodríguez-Alcalá: A Bibliography, 1937-1981. Hugo Rodríguez-Alcalá. Recreación del tiempo perdido en El canto del Aljibe. Américo Castro. Cevantes y Pirandello, un estudi comparativo. Raquel Chang-Rodríguez. El Cautiverio feliz y la narrativa histórico-literaria en Indias. Theodore S. Beardslay, Jr. Algunos manuscritos hispanoaméricanos en The Hispanic Society of America. Alfred Roggiano. Las dos anticipaciones de Espinosa Medrano, "El Lunarejo." (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Michael Palencia-Roth. Entre dos mundos: La cuentística de García Márquez (1968-1972). Allen Phillips. El oro de Mallorca: Textos desconocidos y Breve comentario sobre la novela autobiográfica de Darío. Barbara Jarvis. Who are los de abajo? Enrique Pupo-Walker. La evolución textual en Los de abajo: apuntes sobre el desarrollo artístico de la novela. Seymour Menton. La extructura épica de Los de abajo. Rolando Romero. René Aviles Fabila: Entrevista. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Ernesto Pardo Velásquez. José Tomás de Cuellar (1830-1894). Biografía. Anonymous. Cruz, Sor Juana Inés de la. Biografía. G. C. Flynn. Textual Control of the Imagination: The Criticism of Sor Juana Inés de la Cruz. Sandra Cypess. The Narrator as Ni~na in Balún Canán by Rosario Castellanos. (2 copies) Sandra Cypess. The Power and the Word in Balún Canán. María del Carmen Millán. Campo, Angel de (1868-1908. Biografía. Inés Arredondo. Valoración. Fray Toribio de Benavente. José Rojas Garcidue~nas. Balbuena, Bernardo de (1562?-1627). Biografía. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - 18 anonymous essays on Juan Rulfo (Oklahoma State University). 1-9 (cont....) (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - 18 anonymous essays on Juan Rulfo (Oklahoma State University). 10-18 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Carol D'Lugo. Pedro Páramo: The reader's journey through the text. M. A. Serna-Maytorena. Proposal: Aproximaciones y reintegros a la cuentística Rulfiana. Arthur Ramírez. Spatial form and cinema techniques in Rulfo's Pedro Páramo. M. A. Serna-Maytorena. Del mujerío a la mujer: Notas en torno al personaje femenino en Rulfo. Adelfo Aldana. El bilinguismo en los países americanos: Rémora o estímulo para la literatura en español. Angel Luis Morales. Concha Meléndez y el ensayo de crítica literaria. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - (Cont. from Box 16-Folder 3) Jorge Pratt. 19th Century mexican literature (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Marvin D'Lugo. Frutos de los "Frutos prohibidos": La fantaciencia rioplatense. Paul B. Dixon. O sósia e o quiasmo no conto "Unos brancos" de Machado de Asis. (Actos de Primero Congreso de Associación Internacional de Luistanistas). Richard A. Valdés. A tentative thesis proposal: The philosophical theories in the prose of Jorge Luis Borges. María Zielina. Más allá del color local: Literatura y esclavitud. Rima Vallbona. Mujeres y agonías. Fernando Curiel. The controversy surrounding Martín Luis Guzmán. Atsuko Tanabe. José Juan Tablada and his japonism. G. M. Gugelberger. Them in our literature and we in theirs. Geo-Thematics Reconsidered and Reversed: German-African and Afro-German Images. Macario Ramos Chávez.El Paso (Cuento) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - (These are names that did not appear on original Luis Leal folder, but, belongs to unpublished muscripts by authors and researchers. They were together with the rest on Box D-23). Francisco A. Lomeli. Los mitos de la mexicanidad en la trilogía de Rodolfo Usigli. Eliud Martínez. Mariano Azuela and "The height of the times": A study of La Luciernaga. Raúl H. Padilla. El doble. Kemy Oyarzún."Edipo, autogestion y producción textual: Notas sobre critica literaria feminista" has been accepted for publication in a thematic issue on latin american feminist literary criticism, Herman Vidal, ed. Ideologies and literature, summer 1988. A bibliography of the works of Artemio de Valle-Arizpe. Jaime Giordano.Visconcelos, puente entre dos momentos del pensamiento hispanoaméricano: Entre el positivismo y el existencialismo. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - (These are names that did not appear on original Luis Leal folder, but, belongs to unpublished manuscripts by authors and researchers. They were together with the rest on Box D-23). Mocedades de Vasconcelos by John Skirius. Genesis de Vasconcelos by John Skirius. The Cycles of History and Memory: Las vueltas del tiempo, a novel by Agustín Yáñez, by John Skirius. El '68 y sus letras, Martha Robles. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - (These are names that did not appear on original Luis Leal folder, but, belongs to unpublished manuscripts by authors and researchers. They were together with the rest on Box D-23). Cuentos misteriosos de Amado Nervo, M.A. Serna-Maytorena. Los Cuentos misteriosos de Amado Nervo, Margaret Snook. Impresos raros de los siglos XVII de Juana de Palafox y Mendoza (1600-1659), Obispo de Puebla, en la biblioteca de la Universidad de Illinois por Joseph L. Laurenti y Alberto Porqueras Mayo. El tiempo tublado: Rasgos del ensayo de Octavio Paz sobre la politica contemporanea, Joaguín Roy, University of Miami. Mito y desmitificación en El luto humano, Helia Sheldon, Pitzer Collage. Las fuentes chinas de José Juan Tablada, Adriana García de Aldridge. "Visión de la frontera méxico-texana, 1948: Murieron a mitad del río por Luis Spota", Margarita Cota-Cárdenas. Un análisis de Casi el paraíso de Luis Spota, Richard Reeve. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - (These are names that did not appear on original Luis Leal folder, but, belongs to unpublished manuscripts by authors and researchers. They were together with the rest on Box D-23). Salomon Lipp. Leopoldo Zea and his circumstance "Mexicanness": an attempted definition. Paul Muños. Description of proposal. Lorena M. Parlee. The impact of United States railroad unions on organized labor and government policy in Mexico (1880-1911). (Box 19, Folder 6)